Boston Dispensary Records MS214
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- X-Ray department records, 1911 -- 1966; MS214.008; 2.4 Linear Feet
  This series contains the general correspondence files of the New England Medical Center's Radiology medical directors. The files document personnel appointments, equipment, training programs, and primarily financial decisions. As such, there are contracts, surveys, reports, and budgets of various types of equipment, including deep therapy and cinereadiography. More recent records include information on the planning for the Department of Therapeutic Radiology.
  - Correspondence, 1911 -- 1922; MS214.008.006.00004 (Box MS214 Shared 6)
  - Correspondence, 1923 -- 1933; MS214.008.006.00005 (Box MS214 Shared 6)
  - Correspondence and accounts, 1932 -- 1963; MS214.008.006.00006 (Box MS214 Shared 6)
    Includes quotes, invoices, brochures.
  - Correspondence and accounts, 1932 -- 1957; MS214.008.006.00007 (Box MS214 Shared 6)
    Includes quotes, invoices, brochures, and patient lists.
  - Correspondence and accounts, 1933 -- 1954; MS214.008.006.00008 (Box MS214 Shared 6)
  - Cinereadiographic equipment, 1938 -- 1956; MS214.008.006.00009 (Box MS214 Shared 6)
    Includes the will of Charles A. King.
  - Contract for new equipment, 1942 -- 1949; MS214.008.006.00010 (Box MS214 Shared 6)
    Includes deep therapy.
  - Survey and report on X-Ray equipment, 1942; MS214.008.006.00011; J. Cramer Hudson (Box MS214 Shared 6)
  - Fee schedule study, 1953; MS214.008.006.00012 (Box MS214 Shared 6)
  - Group therapy, 1957; MS214.008.006.00013 (Box MS214 Shared 6)
  - Fee schedule, 1962; MS214.008.006.00014 (Box MS214 Shared 6)
    Also includes a glossery of terminology for ordering x-ray examinations.
  - Radiologist committee, 1960 -- 1962; MS214.008.012.00021 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - X-Ray charges, 1958 -- 1959; MS214.008.012.00022 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Joint conference committee, 1964 -- 1965; MS214.008.012.00023 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Emergency call system, 1959 -- 1960; MS214.008.012.00024 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Residency on call, 1958; MS214.008.012.00025 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Research committee, 1963 -- 1965; MS214.008.012.00026 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Hospital use committee, 1963; MS214.008.012.00027 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Residency training, correspondence and applications, 1963; MS214.008.012.00028 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Picker, quotation for new equipment and room, miscellaneous quotations, 1963; MS214.008.012.00029 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Equipment - Philips, 1960; MS214.008.012.00030 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - New England Center Hospital, 1952 -- 1958; MS214.008.012.00031 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Dean Hayman, 1966; MS214.008.012.00032 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Administrative staff meeting minutes, 1963; MS214.008.012.00033 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Dr. Jaffe, correspondence, 1962; MS214.008.012.00034 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Dr. Ettinger, correspondence, 1962 -- 1965; MS214.008.012.00035 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - General correspondence, 1942 -- 1965; MS214.008.012.00036 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Miss Dunks, Mr. McTernan, Mr. Grace, 1962 -- 1965; MS214.008.012.00037 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Cineradiographic studies, 1959; MS214.008.012.00038 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
- United Services Committee correspondence, 1947 -- 1965; MS214.009; 1.2 Linear Feet
  The bulk of this series contains general correspondence, but several folders also include financial and campaign information, as well as a study of the relationship between the Boston Dispensary and the United Community Services (UCS) conducted in the late-1950s.
  - Board committee to study relationship of Boston Dispensary to UCS, 1953 -- 1959; MS214.009.010.00001 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - UCS general correspondence, 1955 -- 1960; MS214.009.010.00002 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - UCS general correspondence, 1961; MS214.009.010.00003 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - UCS general financial correspondence, 1951 -- 1964; MS214.009.010.00004 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - UCS December Fundraising Campaign, 1958 -- 1962; MS214.009.010.00005 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - UCS United Fund Campaign, 1963; MS214.009.010.00006 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - UCS United Fund Campaign, 1964; MS214.009.010.00007 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - UCS Committee on Rehabilitation, 1957; MS214.009.010.00008 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - UCS Rehabilitation Services and Fee Study Committee, 1959 -- 1963; MS214.009.010.00009 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - UCS general correspondence, 1949 -- 1965; MS214.009.010.00010 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - American Dietetic Association, 1960 -- 1963; MS214.009.010.00011 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - US Public Health Service, 1948 -- 1949; MS214.009.010.00012 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - UCS rehabilitation council fee study committee definitions, 1959 -- 1964; MS214.009.010.00013 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, A, 1960 -- 1964; MS214.009.010.00014 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, C, 1962 -- 1964; MS214.009.010.00015 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, D, 1956 -- 1964; MS214.009.010.00016 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, E, 1964; MS214.009.010.00017 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, F, 1958 -- 1962; MS214.009.010.00018 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, G, 1961 -- 1962; MS214.009.010.00019 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, H, 1962 -- 1964; MS214.009.010.00020 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, I, 1957; MS214.009.010.00021 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, J, 1961; MS214.009.010.00022 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, K, 1958 -- 1963; MS214.009.010.00023 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, L, 1963; MS214.009.010.00024 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, M, 1960 -- 1962; MS214.009.010.00025 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, N, 1947 -- 1962; MS214.009.010.00026 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, O, 1947 -- 1954; MS214.009.010.00027 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, P, 1960 -- 1962; MS214.009.010.00028 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, Q, 1956 -- 1961; MS214.009.010.00029 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, R, 1958 -- 1964; MS214.009.010.00030 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, S, 1959 -- 1965; MS214.009.010.00031 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, T, 1949 -- 1961; MS214.009.010.00032 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, U, 1948 -- 1961; MS214.009.010.00033 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
  - General correspondence, W, 1949 -- 1963; MS214.009.010.00034 (Box MS214 Shared 7)
- Clinical correspondence, agreements, and contracts, 1916 -- 1965; MS214.010; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains correspondence of various clinics within the Dispensary, agreements between departments, and contracts. Of particular note is the 1930 agreement that established NEMC, and a set of blueprints for the Dispensary from 1929.
  Correspondence from the department of Psychiatry containing patient information has been restricted.
  - Contracts, building and alterations, 1937; MS214.010.009.00001 (Box 9)
  - NEMC contracts, Tamblyn and Brown campaign, 1929 -- 1952; MS214.010.009.00002 (Box 9)
  - BD annual reports, 1916 -- 1921; MS214.010.009.00003 (Box 9)
  - Davis, Michael, letter of recognition, 1920; MS214.010.009.00004 (Box 9)
  - Contracts, Deep Therapy Equipment, 1936 -- 1939; MS214.010.009.00005 (Box 9)
  - Contracts, Mallinchrodt Chemical (Pharmacy), Parker-Davis Co., Smith Kline and French, 1946 -- 1960; MS214.010.009.00006 (Box 9)
  - Contracts, air-conditioning contract, 1949 -- 1951; MS214.010.009.00007 (Box 9)
  - Medical record equipment contract, 1950; MS214.010.009.00008 (Box 9)
  - Contracts, elevator maintenance, 1940 -- 1960; MS214.010.009.00009 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous NEMC contracts and agreements, 1931 -- 1949; MS214.010.009.00010 (Box 9)
  - Contracts, miscellaneous supplies and services, 1940 -- 1953; MS214.010.009.00011 (Box 9)
  - Surgical podiatry, 1960; MS214.010.009.00012 (Box 9)
  - Agreements with fundraisers, 1921 -- 1923; MS214.010.009.00013 (Box 9)
  - NECH, contracts, construction, 1930; MS214.010.009.00014 (Box 9)
  - South End Diet Kitchen, certification of organization memorandum of agreement, 1956; MS214.010.009.00015 (Box 9)
  - Thoracic Clinic, 1936 -- 1948; MS214.010.009.00016 (Box 9)
  - Cancer Program Plans, 1963; MS214.010.009.00017 (Box 9)
  - Urology clinic, 1922 -- 1959; MS214.010.009.00018 (Box 9)
  - Visiting Nurse Association of Boston, 1958 -- 1963; MS214.010.009.00019 (Box 9)
  - BU Human Relations Study, 1956; MS214.010.009.00020 (Box 9)
  - Complaints district, 1939 -- 1943; MS214.010.009.00021 (Box 9)
  - Blue prints, 1929; MS214.010.009.00022 (Box 9)
  - Boston Dispensary, complaints, 1930; MS214.010.009.00023 (Box 9)
  - NEMC, acts, state legislature, authorizing incorporation, 1930 -- 1959; MS214.010.009.00024 (Box 9)
  - NECH agreement, 1949; MS214.010.009.00025 (Box 9)
  - Agreement, correspondence, Ropes and Gray, 1929 -- 1949; MS214.010.009.00026 (Box 9)
  - Contract, Pratt Diagnostic Hospital Boston Dispensary specification, 1937; MS214.010.009.00027 (Box 9)
  - BD blueprints and specifications, alterations, 1937; MS214.010.009.00028 (Box 9)
  - Contracts, alterations in main laboratory, 1939 -- 1940; MS214.010.009.00029 (Box 9)
  - Multiple Sclerosis Clinic, 1955; MS214.010.009.00030 (Box 9)
  - Orthopedic services, 1954; MS214.010.009.00031 (Box 9)
  - Preventive, general correspondence, 1959; MS214.010.009.00032 (Box 9)
  - Psychotherapy, group experiment, 1959; MS214.010.009.00033 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, department of psychiatry, 1948 -- 1959; MS214.010.009.00034 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, Rectal Clinic, 1938 -- 1957; MS214.010.009.00035 (Box 9)
  - Surgical, general, 1960; MS214.010.009.00036 (Box 9)
  - Consultation and Diagnostic Service, 1957; MS214.010.009.00037 (Box 9)
  - Consultation and Diagnostic Service, correspondence, 1944; MS214.010.009.00038 (Box 9)
  - Dental clinic, Tufts College, 1949; MS214.010.009.00039 (Box 9)
  - Diabetic clinic, 1958 -- 1961; MS214.010.009.00040 (Box 9)
  - Clinic departments, evening clinic, 1956 -- 1959; MS214.010.009.00041 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, eye clinic, 1957 -- 1963; MS214.010.009.00042 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, Gynecological, 1960 -- 1962; MS214.010.009.00043 (Box 9)
  - Multiple Sclerosis Clinic reports, 1955; MS214.010.009.00044 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, clinical departments, 1939 -- 1951; MS214.010.009.00045 (Box 9)
  - Clinic schedules, 1960 -- 1961; MS214.010.009.00046 (Box 9)
  - Admissions clinic, 1950 -- 1961; MS214.010.009.00047 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, allergy and social services, 1940 -- 1945; MS214.010.009.00048 (Box 9)
  - Arthritis clinic, 1940 -- 1965; MS214.010.009.00049 (Box 9)
  - Arthritis training grant, 1955 -- 1957; MS214.010.009.00050 (Box 9)
  - Cardiac clinic cardiac payments, 1960; MS214.010.009.00051 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, children's clinic, 1960 -- 1962; MS214.010.009.00052 (Box 9)
  - Circulatory clinic, 1940 -- 1943; MS214.010.009.00053 (Box 9)
  - Child guidance clinic, 1960; MS214.010.009.00054 (Box 9)
  - Allergy clinic, 1960; MS214.010.009.00055 (Box 9)
  - Cardiac clinic, 1954 -- 1965; MS214.010.009.00056 (Box 9)
  - Cardiac clinic state aided cardiac clinic monthly reports, 1958 -- 1963; MS214.010.009.00057 (Box 9)
  - Group therapy general correspondence, 1936 -- 1960; MS214.010.009.00058 (Box 9)
  - The Family Internist and the University Medical Center, 1962; MS214.010.009.00059 (Box 9)
  - Medical morning and afternoon general correspondence, 1956; MS214.010.009.00060 (Box 9)
- Massachusetts Department of Public Health records, 1915 -- 1983; MS214.011; 2.4 Linear Feet
  This series contains administrative files and correspondence.
  - Commonwealth of Massachusetts Division of Venereal Diseases correspondence, 1946 -- 1958; MS214.011.011.00037 (Box MS214 Shared 8)
  - Venereal Diseases correspondence and salaries, 1958 -- 1965; MS214.011.011.00038 (Box MS214 Shared 8)
  - Bureau hospital facilities correspondence, Dr. Rubenstein, 1958 -- 1963; MS214.011.011.00039 (Box MS214 Shared 8)
  - Salstonstall, William, 1979 -- 1983; MS214.011.011.00040 (Box MS214 Shared 8)
  - License, Boston Dispensary, 1964 -- 1965; MS214.011.011.00041 (Box MS214 Shared 8)
  - Division of Food and Drugs, 1957 -- 1958; MS214.011.011.00042 (Box MS214 Shared 8)
  - Massachusetts Medical Society, 1930 -- 1963; MS214.011.012.00001 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Rehabilitation Institute Blue Cross matters, 1958 -- 1960; MS214.011.012.00002 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Commonwealth of Massachusetts general correspondence, 1957 -- 1963; MS214.011.012.00003 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Venereal diseases lab reports, 1961 -- 1965; MS214.011.012.00004 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Division of Venereal Diseases, reports, 1960 -- 1965; MS214.011.012.00005 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Reports, Bureau Hospital Facilities, 1955 -- 1964; MS214.011.012.00006 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, 1939 -- 1962; MS214.011.012.00007 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Maternal, Child Health Division, 1957 -- 1964; MS214.011.012.00008 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Blue Cross contract, 1959; MS214.011.012.00009 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Massachusetts Memorial Hospitals, 1957 -- 1960; MS214.011.012.00010 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Morgan Memorial Inc., 1955 -- 1963; MS214.011.012.00011 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Massachusetts Hospital Service general correspondence, 1957 -- 1965; MS214.011.012.00012 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Medical Care Plan fees, 1960; MS214.011.012.00013 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Medical Care Plan fees, 1961; MS214.011.012.00014 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - General correspondence, 1941 -- 1965; MS214.011.012.00015 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Massachusetts Hospital Service contracts and agreements, 1948 -- 1957; MS214.011.012.00016 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Rehabilitation Institute License, 1915 -- 1963; MS214.011.012.00017 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Boston Dispensary Rehabilitation Institute, 1958; MS214.011.012.00018 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Massachusetts Department of Mental Health, 1958; MS214.011.012.00019 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
  - Massachusetts Department of Labor and Industries Minimum Wage Commission, 1942; MS214.011.012.00020 (Box MS214 Shared 3)
- Board of Trustees records, 1796 -- 1910; MS214.012
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Materials in this series were transferred to DCA by the Francis A. Countway Library of Medicine in August 2016.
  - Meeting minutes, 1796 -- 1827; MS214.012.015.00001 (Box 15, Volume 1)
  - Visiting Committee, register of visits, 1856 -- 1910; MS214.012.015.00002 (Box 15, Volume 2)
  - Meeting minutes, 1827 -- 1856; MS214.012.015.00003 (Box 15, Volume 3)
  - Minutes, 1856 -- 1876; MS214.012.015.00004 (Box 15, Volume 3)
  - Minutes, 1876 -- 1898; MS214.012.015.00005 (Box 15, Volume 5)
  - Minutes, 1898 -- 1910; MS214.012.015.00006 (Box 15, Volume 6)
  - Boston Dispensary Bylaws, 1829; MS214.012.024.0153 (Box 24, Folder 153)
  - Rules of Incorporation, printed, 1851; MS214.012.024.00154 (Box 24, Folder 154)
  - Bylaws, 1855; MS214.012.024.00155 (Box 24, Folder 155)
  - Additional Acts of Incorporation, 1859; MS214.012.024.000156 (Box 24, Folder 156)
  - Board - Notice of meeting and correspondence, 1797 -- 1801, 1809 -- 1814; MS214.012.024.00157 (Box 24, Folder 157)
  - Board - Notice of meetings, 1843; MS214.012.024.00158 (Box 24, Folder 158)
  - Board - Committees - including "Anniversary", 1843; MS214.012.024.00159 (Box 24, Folder 159)
  - Board vote to authorize use of nurses in "Special Cases", 1838; MS214.012.024.00160 (Box 24, Folder 160)
  - Board committee on relief, reports, 1838; MS214.012.024.00161 (Box 24, Folder 161)
  - Board - reports - committee on the selection of candidates for the board of managers, 1840; MS214.012.024.00162 (Box 24, Folder 162)
  - Apothecary Committee and Opening of Central Shop, 1845 -- 1846; MS214.012.024.00163 (Box 24, Folder 163)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1856 --1859; MS214.012.024.00164 (Box 24, Folder 164)
  - Executive Committee authorizes purchase of Ash Street property, 1855 -- 1856; MS214.012.024.00165 (Box 24, Folder 165)
  - Bennet St., Ash St., Purchase and fitting up of property, Executive Committee report, 1855; MS214.012.024.00166 (Box 24, Folder 166)
  - Executive Committee - report, re: Establishment of VD Clinic at BN, 1864; MS214.012.024.00167 (Box 24, Folder 167)
  - Correspondence - Executive Committee to Board, re: Salary of H. Damin, Superintendent, 1864; MS214.012.024.00168 (Box 24, Folder 168)
  - Board Meeting, re: increase in Superintendent salary, 1874; MS214.012.024.00169 (Box 24, Folder 169)
  - Letter from Board Urging Restriction of Wine, published as circular to physicians, 1812; MS214.012.024.00170 (Box 24, Folder 170)
  - Correspondence - Physicians to Board J. Bigelow on behalf of Staff, re: "no wine", 1812; MS214.012.024.00171 (Box 24, Folder 171)
  - Correspondence - Board - Letter to Board, re: "too many" physicians and medical students, and treatment of "unworthy" patients, 1830; MS214.012.024.00172 (Box 24, Folder 172)
  - Letter enclosed with report, re: intemperance and charity, 1833; MS214.012.024.00173 (Box 24, Folder 173)
  - Correspondence - Petition from Physicians, re: "uniformity of terms", 1833; MS214.012.024.00174 (Box 24, Folder 174)
  - Standardizing "Nomenclature", 1833; MS214.012.024.00175 (Box 24, Folder 175)
  - Correspondence - G. Snelling, Secretary, letter, re: Physicians delegating responsiblity to others - a "violation" of the "rules of the institution", 1834; MS214.012.024.00176 (Box 24, Folder 176)
  - Correspondence Board - Letter for George Thayer - re: the term and the residence of the physician in the district to each physician has been appointed, 1838; MS214.012.024.00177 (Box 24, Folder 177)
  - Correspondence - Petition of District Physicians for Salary - $100 per annum - signed by staff, 1842; MS214.012.024.00178 (Box 24, Folder 178)
  - Board recommends scarification over leeches, 1844; MS214.012.024.00179 (Box 24, Folder 179)
  - Correspondence - Board to physicians and reply - scarification vs use of leeches and use of "cupping machine", 1844; MS214.012.024.00180 (Box 24, Folder 180)
  - Correspondence - Dr. C.W. Moore to Board, re: Use of local pharmacies and cost per patient, 1853; MS214.012.024.00181 (Box 24, Folder 181)
  - Correspondence - Dr. Henry Bigelow, re: Payment of Physicians, 1855; MS214.012.024.00182 (Box 24, Folder 182)
  - Analysis and abstract - Dr. W. R. Lawrence, 1850; MS214.012.024.00183 (Box 24, Folder 183)
  - Statistics of London Dispensary by D. Lawrence, 1856; MS214.012.024.00184 (Box 24, Folder 184)
  - Correspondence - William Coolidge - Eastern Dispensary, New York City, NY to Board re: statistics of U.S. Dispensaries, 1859; MS214.012.024.00185 (Box 24, Folder 185)
  - Reverend Joseph Eckley, President of Board - resignation, 1803; MS214.012.024.00186 (Box 24, Folder 186)
  - Benjamin West, Secretary - resignation, 1819; MS214.012.024.00187 (Box 24, Folder 187)
  - Report of Committee on gift of plate to G. Snow, 1844; MS214.012.024.00188 (Box 24, Folder 188)
  - Correspondence - George Thape to William Gray re: permission to Gray to enjoy privilege of subscriber, 1847-10-18; MS214.012.024.00189 (Box 24, Folder 189)
  - Treasurer - George Bigelow - resignation, 1850; MS214.012.024.00190 (Box 24, Folder 190)
  - Letter soliciting funds and response from Board of Boston lying in hospital, 1858-1860; MS214.012.024.00191 (Box 24, Folder 191)
  - G. E. Guild - resignation from Board, 1858; MS214.012.024.00192 (Box 24, Folder 192)
  - Correspondence - letter and subscription re: "sea voyage" for physician with terminal disease, 1859; MS214.012.024.00193 (Box 24, Folder 193)
  - Correspondence - Boston Athenaeum - acknowledges receipt of Boston Dispensary of annual report, 1858; MS214.012.024.00194 (Box 24, Folder 194)
  - Boston Public Library - Acknowledgement of gift of bylaws, 1860; MS214.012.024.00195 (Box 24, Folder 195)
  - Correspondence - Board re: endorsement of Free City Hospital, 1860; MS214.012.024.00196 (Box 24, Folder 196)
  - Sammuel Eliot - declines Board appointment, 1871; MS214.012.024.00197 (Box 24, Folder 197)
  - Bills and receipts - rental of Massachusetts Bank Hall, 1818-1832; MS214.012.024.00198 (Box 24, Folder 198)
  - 109 Washington Street - receipts for rent, 1841-1846; MS214.012.024.00199 (Box 24, Folder 199)
  - Maverick Street, East Boston - house insurance and correspondence, 1850; MS214.012.024.00200 (Box 24, Folder 200)
  - 3 Summer Street rent receipts, 1855-1859; MS214.012.024.00201 (Box 24, Folder 201)
  - Dennet Street - lease of house, 1857-1858; MS214.012.024.00202 (Box 24, Folder 202)
  - Treasurer - E. Blake - correspondence re: mortgage, 1857-1858; MS214.012.024.00203 (Box 24, Folder 203)
  - Ash Street and Bennet Street - bills for services, 1856-1857; MS214.012.024.00204 (Box 24, Folder 204)
  - Correspondence - Channing Street Home for the Sick and Destitute to Board re: lease of Bennet Street property, 1858; MS214.012.024.00205 (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Bennet Street and Ash Street - fire insurance on Central Office adjoining building, 1862; MS214.012.024.00206 (Box 24, Folder 206)
  - Bennet Street - fire insurance, 1873; MS214.012.024.00207 (Box 24, Folder 207)
- Superintendent records, 1823 -- 1911; MS214.013
  - Quarterly and annual reports, 1856 -- 1866; MS214.013.016.00008 (Box 16, Volume 8)
  - Quarterly and annual reports, 1867 -- 1876; MS214.013.016.00006 (Box 16, Volume 6)
  - Quarterly and annual reports, 1877 -- 1883; MS214.013.016.00007 (Box 16, Volume 7)
  - Quarterly and annual reports, 1884 -- 1890; MS214.013.016.00004 (Box 16, Volume 4)
  - Quarterly and annual reports, 1891 -- 1896; MS214.013.016.00005 (Box 16, Volume 5)
  - Quarterly and annual reports, 1897 -- 1903; MS214.013.016.00003 (Box 16, Volume 3)
  - Quarterly and annual reports, 1903 -- 1910; MS214.013.016.00002 (Box 16, Volume 2)
  - Daily record of house patients, 1897 -- 1905; MS214.013.016.00001 (Box 16, Volume 1)
  - Annual report, 1858 -- 1883; MS214.013.024.00208 (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Annual report, 1890 -- 1904; MS214.013.024.00209 (Box 24, Folder 209)
  - Annual report, 1908 -- 1909; MS214.013.024.00210 (Box 24, Folder 210)
  - Superintendent's accounts - J. B. Alley, 1858 -- 1859; MS214.013.024.00211 (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Superintendent's accounts - J. B. Alley, 1860; MS214.013.024.00212 (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Superintendent's accounts - J. B. Alley, 1861 -- 1862; MS214.013.024.00213 (Box 24, Folder 213)
  - Superintendent's accounts - H. F. Damon, 1863 -- 1865; MS214.013.024.00214 (Box 24, Folder 214)
  - Superintendent's accounts - Daily journal of Edward Otis, 1903-04-1903-10; MS214.013.024.00215 (Box 24, Folder 215)
  - Inventory for insurance - General rooms, maintenance, summary of statistics, 1900; MS214.013.024.00216 (Box 24, Folder 216)
  - Inventory for insurance - Clinical departments and pharmacy, 1900; MS214.013.024.00217 (Box 24, Folder 217)
  - Bills and receipts - Messenger's service, 1797 -- 1803; MS214.013.024.00218 (Box 24, Folder 218)
  - Bills and receipts - Messenger's service, 1806 -- 1812; MS214.013.024.00219 (Box 24, Folder 219)
  - Bills and receipts - Collecting subscriptions, 1810 -- 1815; MS214.013.024.00220 (Box 24, Folder 220)
  - Bills and receipts - Advertising, 1799 -- 1807; MS214.013.024.00221 (Box 24, Folder 221)
  - Bills and receipts - Printing contributors' tickets, 1796; MS214.013.024.00222 (Box 24, Folder 222)
  - Bills and receipts - Printing of "500 Rules for Boston Dispensary Patients", 1799; MS214.013.024.00223 (Box 24, Folder 223)
  - Bills and receipts - Printing vouchers for wine, 1800; MS214.013.024.00224 (Box 24, Folder 224)
  - Bills and receipts - Printing, 1800 -- 1814; MS214.013.024.00225 (Box 24, Folder 225)